<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Traffic Light Control</string>
    <string name="Navigation_drawer_open">open Navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="Navigation_drawer_close">close Navigation drawer</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <string name="defination">
A traffic light is a signaling device used at intersections and pedestrian crossings to control the flow of vehicular and pedestrian traffic.
It consists of a set of colored lights arranged vertically or horizontally, typically red, yellow (or amber), and green. Each color corresponds
to a specific command or instruction for drivers and pedestrians. The traffic light system is designed to promote orderly and safe movement of
vehicles and people at intersections by indicating when to stop, exercise caution, or proceed. \n\n
<b>The standard meanings of the colors on a traffic light are as follows: \n\n</b>
<b><i>Red Light:\n</i></b>
1. Requires vehicles to come to a complete stop.\n
2. No vehicles are allowed to proceed until the light changes.\n\n
<b><i>Yellow (Amber) Light:\n</i></b>
1. Warns that the signal is about to change.\n
2. Drivers should slow down and prepare to stop unless it is unsafe to do so.\n\n
<b><i>Green Light:\n</i></b>
1. Indicates that vehicles have the right of way to proceed.\n
2. Drivers and pedestrians are allowed to move in the direction specified by the green light.\n

</string>

<string name="defination1">
<b>1. General Traffic Rules:\n</b>
. Obey all traffic signs and signals.\n
. Follow posted speed limits.\n
. Drive on the right side of the road, unless otherwise specified.\n\n
<b>2. Traffic Signals:\n</b>
. Adhere to the color-coded signals: red (stop), yellow (caution), and green (go).\n
. Stop completely at red lights.\n
. Proceed with caution at yellow lights.\n
. Move forward when the light turns green.\n\n
<b>3. Intersections:\n</b>
. Yield the right of way to vehicles already in the intersection.\n
. Come to a complete stop at stop signs.\n
. Follow right-of-way rules and regulations.\n\n
<b>4. Turns and Lane Discipline:\n</b>
. Signal well in advance of making a turn.\n
. Make turns from the designated lanes.\n
. Stay in your lane and do not change lanes within intersections.\n\n
<b>5. Speed Limits:\n</b>
. Obey posted speed limits on roads and highways.\n
. Adjust speed based on road conditions, such as weather and visibility.\n\n
<b>6. Overtaking and Passing:\n</b>
. Pass other vehicles only in designated passing zones.\n
. Do not pass in no-passing zones or around curves.\n
. Always signal before changing lanes.\n\n
<b>7. Pedestrian Safety:\n</b>
. Yield to pedestrians in crosswalks.\n
. Stop for pedestrians at intersections, especially at marked crosswalks.\n
. Exercise caution in school zones and residential areas.\n\n
<b>8. School Buses:\n</b>
. Stop when school buses are loading or unloading children and wait until they resume motion.\n\n
<b>9. Railroad Crossings:\n</b>
. Stop at railroad crossings when lights are flashing or barriers are down.\n
. Do not proceed until it is safe to cross.\n\n
<b>10. Seat Belt and Child Restraint:\n</b>
. Wear seat belts at all times.\n
. Use appropriate child safety seats and restraints for young passengers.\n\n
<b>11. Distracted Driving:\n</b>
. Avoid using mobile phones or engaging in distracting activities while driving.\n\n
<b>12. Drinking and Driving:\n</b>
. Do not drive under the influence of alcohol or drugs.\n\n
<b>13. Emergency Vehicles:\n</b>
. Yield the right of way to emergency vehicles with lights and sirens.\n
. Pull over to the right and stop to allow them to pass safely.\n\n
<b>14. Parking Rules:\n</b>
. Park only in designated areas.\n
. Follow parking regulations, including time limits and payment requirements.\n\n
<b>15. Hitchhiking and Panhandling:\n</b>
. Do not pick up hitchhikers for safety reasons.\n
. Avoid engaging with panhandlers on the road.\n\n

</string>




<string name="pedestian">

A pedestrian is an individual who travels on foot, moving from one place to another by walking.
Pedestrians typically use sidewalks, crosswalks, or other designated pedestrian pathways for safe
and orderly travel. \n\n
</string>


<string name="pedestrian1">
<b>Idle State:</b>\n
Description: The traffic light operates in the default vehicle phase.\n
Signals: Vehicle green, pedestrian "DON'T WALK" signal.\n\n
<b>Pedestrian Activation:</b>\n
Trigger: Pedestrian presses the crosswalk button.\n
Action: Initiates the transition to the pedestrian phase.\n\n
<b>Transition to Pedestrian Phase:</b>\n
Action: Switches from the default vehicle phase to the pedestrian phase.\n
Signals: Vehicle red, pedestrian "WALK" signal.\n\n
<b>Green Signal for Pedestrians:</b>\n
Duration: 20 seconds.\n
Description: Pedestrians are allowed to cross the road safely.\n
Signals: Vehicle red, pedestrian "WALK" signal.\n\n
<b>Flashing Red Signal for Pedestrians:</b>\n
Duration: 3 seconds.\n
Description: Pedestrians should finish crossing quickly as the signal is about to change.\n
Signals: Vehicle red, flashing pedestrian "DON'T WALK" signal.\n\n
<b>Red Signal for Pedestrians:</b>\n
Duration: 10 seconds.\n
Description: Pedestrians must not cross the road.\n
Signals: Vehicle red, solid pedestrian "DON'T WALK" signal.\n\n\n\n
 </string>



</resources>